<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">RitchieTanenbaum</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="firstname_lastname_d">Dennis Ritchie</string>
    <string name="firstname_lastname_a">Andrew Tanenbaum</string>
    <string name="descriptiond">Dennis MacAlistair Ritchie (September 9, 1941 – c. October 12, 2011) was an American computer scientist who \"helped shape the digital era.\" He created the C programming language and, with long-time colleague Ken Thompson, the Unix operating system. Ritchie and Thompson received the Turing Award from the ACM in 1983, the Hamming Medal from the IEEE in 1990 and the National Medal of Technology from President Clinton in 1999. Ritchie was the head of Lucent Technologies System Software Research Department when he retired in 2007. He was the \'R\' in K&amp;R C and commonly known by his username \"dmr\".\nRitchie was born in Bronxville, New York. His father was Alistair E. Ritchie, a longtime Bell Labs scientist and co-author of The Design of Switching Circuits on switching circuit theory. He moved with his family to Summit, New Jersey, as a child, where he graduated from Summit High School.\nRitchie graduated from Harvard University with degrees in physics and applied mathematics. In 1967, he began working at the Bell Labs Computing Sciences Research Center, and in 1968, he received a PhD from Harvard under the supervision of Patrick C. Fischer, his doctoral dissertation being \"Program Structure and Computational Complexity\". Ritchie was best known as the creator of the C programming language, a key developer of the Unix operating system, and co-author of the book The C Programming Language, and was the \'R\' in K&amp;R (a common reference to the book\'s authors Kernighan and Ritchie). Ritchie worked together with Ken Thompson, the scientist credited with writing the original Unix; one of Ritchie\'s most important contributions to Unix was its porting to different machines and platforms. The C language is widely used today in application, operating system, and embedded system development, and its influence is seen in most modern programming languages. Unix has also been influential, establishing concepts and principles that are now precepts of computing.\nRitchie was found dead on October 12, 2011, at the age of 70 at his home in Berkeley Heights, New Jersey, where he lived alone. First news of his death came from his former colleague, Rob Pike. The cause and exact time of death have not been disclosed. He had been in frail health for several years following treatment for prostate cancer and heart disease. His death came a week after the death of Steve Jobs but did not receive as much media coverage. Computer historian Paul E. Ceruzzi said after his death: \"Ritchie was under the radar. His name was not a household name at all, but&#8230; if you had a microscope and could look in a computer, you\'d see his work everywhere inside.\" In an interview shortly after Ritchie\'s death, long time colleague Brian Kernighan said Ritchie never expected C to be so significant. Kernighan reminded readers of how important a role C and UNIX had played in the development of later high-profile projects, like the iPhone. Other testimonials to his influence followed. The Fedora 16 Linux distribution, which was released about a month after he died, was dedicated to his memory. FreeBSD 9.0, released January 12, 2012 was also dedicated in his memory. - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</string>
    <string name="descriptiona">Andrew Stuart \"Andy\" Tanenbaum (sometimes referred to by the handle \"ast\") (born March 16, 1944) is an American computer scientist and professor of computer science at the Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam in the Netherlands. He is best known as the author of MINIX, a free Unix-like operating system for teaching purposes, and for his computer science textbooks, regarded as standard texts in the field. He regards his teaching job as his most important work. Since 2004 he has operated Electoral-vote.com, a website dedicated to analysis of polling data in federal elections in the United States.\nHe was born in New York City and grew up in suburban White Plains, New York. He received his bachelor of Science degree in Physics from MIT in 1965 and his Ph.D. degree in physics from the University of California, Berkeley in 1971. Tanenbaum also served as a lobbyist for the Sierra Club. He moved to the Netherlands to live with his wife, who is Dutch, but he retains his United States citizenship. He teaches courses about Computer Organization and Operating Systems and supervises the work of Ph.D. candidates at the VU University Amsterdam.\nHe is well recognized for his textbooks on computer science: Computer Networks, co-authored with David J. Wetherall, Operating Systems: Design and Implementation, co-authored with Albert Woodhull, Modern Operating Systems, Distributed Operating Systems, Structured Computer Organization, Distributed Systems: Principles and Paradigms, co-authored with Maarten van Steen, Operating Systems: Design and Implementation and MINIX were Linus Torvalds\' inspiration for the Linux kernel. In his autobiography Just for Fun, Torvalds describes it as \"the book that launched me to new heights\". His books have been translated into many languages including Arabic, Basque, Bulgarian, Chinese, Dutch, French, German, Greek, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Macedonian, Mexican Spanish, Persian, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Russian, Serbian, Spanish. They have appeared in over 120 editions and are used at universities around the world.\nTanenbaum has had a number of Ph.D. students who themselves have gone on to become widely known computer science researchers. These include: Henri Bal, a professor at the Vrije Universiteit in Amsterdam; Frans Kaashoek, a professor at MIT; Sape Mullender, a researcher at Bell Labs; Robbert van Renesse, a professor at Cornell University; Leendert van Doorn, a fellow at the AMD Corporation; Werner Vogels, the Chief Technology Officer at Amazon.com. Tanenbaum has also been involved in numerous other research projects in the areas of operating systems, distributed systems, and ubiquitous computing, often as supervisor of Ph.D. students or a postdoctoral researcher. These projects include: Amoeba, Globe, Mansion, Orca, Paramecium, RFID Guardian, Turtle F2F. - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</string>

</resources>
